I remember the magic spell
From back when a rainbow stretched across the sky
In an instant, every corner of the world
Took on a brilliant hue
The voice of my heart
Always illuminates the path I need to take
It is because I doubt everything
That I know it to be true
Why does my heart still beat?
Why do my lungs still breathe?
Why is my chest burning with passion?
There's a reason for all of that
And, like the starry sky hidden behind the clouds
Like the ticket to a destination I lost somewhere
Like the history of the world from before I was born
You hold the answer just beyond my reach
If nothing else, I know that all too well
If nobody else, I know that all too well
Kiriyama Rei
（幸田(こうだ)香子(きょうこ)）
ゼロだって… 変な名前
Zero?
What a weird name.
But it suits you.
でも ぴったりよね あなたに…
だって そうでしょ？
Doesn't it?
家も無い 家族も無い
You don't have a home.
You don't have a family.
学校にも行ってない
You don't go to school.
You don't have any friends.
友達もいない…
See? There's no place for you in this world.
ほら あなたの居場所なんて
この世のどこにも無いじゃない
（桐山(きりやま) 零(れい)）あっ ああ…
I closed my eyes to calm myself down
Under the moonlight
How I love this place
I must leave at once
I may have understood
I was sealed in grief
In fact, I'm afraid even in my home
How sad every day was
I'm filled with love
I had tears in my eyes
But now I can change the murky colors of my life
How far should I keep swimming?
How long until it finally stops raining?
I don't know how to walk, even when I'm wet
Looking for my nest in this dark city
I see a giant rainbow
Shogi
Hall
The calm mind
is the way
How have you been, Rei?
（幸田(こうだ)柾近(まさちか)）元気だったか？ 零
Sure is hot, huh?
（幸田）暑いなぁ…
We're not even in the rainy season yet.
まだ 梅雨にも
入っとらんというのに…
Jeez, what am I saying?
参ったな…
Is the weather really all I can think of talking about?
こんな時だっていうのに
天気の話しか出てこんとは…
Children's Shogi Tournament
Well, let's begin.
じゃあ 始めるか
Winner
Kiriyama Rei
Children's Shogi Tournament
ああ 無いな…
There's nothing.
Yep. Nothing.
うん　無い
負けました
I lost.
You've gotten better.
強くなったな
Are you eating properly?
ちゃんと
食べているのか？
You left so suddenly.
急に出ていって
歩(あゆむ)も香子も心配してるぞ
Ayumu and Kyouko are worried about you too.
うそだ
That's a lie.
Next stop: Tsukishima. Tsukishima.
1 New Message
Inbox
Kawamoto Hinata
Kawamoto Akari
To Kiriyama
Good work today! We're having curry tonight, so come over!
Message
Kawamoto Hinata
To Kiriyama
Good work today! We're having curry tonight, so come over!
We'll be waiting. See you!
-Hinata
Message
Kawamoto Hinata
To Kiriyama
Good work today! We're having curry tonight, so come over!
We'll be waiting. See you!
-Hinata
Draft
Kawamoto Hinata
To Kiriyama
Thank you for the invitation. However, I'm feeling under the weather today, so I think I'll stay home.
Incoming
New message received
Inbox
Kawamoto Akari
Oh no, Rei
We're having curry, but we don't have any pickled vegetables!
Could you please buy some at the convenience
store on your way over? Grab some eggs too!
Thank you!
（コンビニ店員）
ありがとうございました
（川本(かわもと)モモ）
あぁ 零ちゃん 来た！
Rei is here!
I bet you're tired.
（川本あかり）お疲れさま
ごはん できてるよ
Dinner's ready!
Hurry up, Rei!
（川本ひなた）零君
早く 早く！ おなかすいたよ
I'm hungry!
（モモ）零ちゃん アイスは？
（あかり）こら モモ
Rei, did you get ice cream?
Hey, Momo!
（クロちゃん）ニャオー
ああ… 買ってきました
アイスと あと… プリンも
I did.
I also grabbed some pudding.
（モモ）アイス！
（ひなた）プリン！
Ice cream!
Pudding!
Yay!
Hina, you too?
（あかり）ヒナも もう〜
Yay!
（モモ）うわぁ！
牛乳のプリンだ〜
Milk pudding!
Zoom
Oh my, you bought all this?
（あかり）あらあら こんなに？
Thank you.
ありがとね
（ひなた）アイスしまうとこ
空けてくるね
I'll make room for the ice cream!
Bloomph
I'll pay you back.
（あかり）でも お金払うよ
高かったでしょう？
This must've been expensive, right?
Don't worry. It's a gift.
ああ いえ… お土産ですから
Also, sorry. I didn't know which one to get,
so I ended up buying a lot.
でも すみません…
どれがいいのか分からなくて
こんなにいっぱいに…
I'm happy with this.
（クロちゃん）ミーは これで…
Oh, that's right.
あっ そうだ
零君 試合どうだった？
How did your match go, Rei?
Sis said it was an important match for your club.
あかり姉ちゃんが言ってたの
部活の大事な試合なんだって
I won.
勝ったよ
ああ そっか　良かった
Oh, that's great!
Sis, feed me! Please feed me!
（クロちゃん）ああ お姉さん
ごはんを ごはんをください
Feed me, feed me! Hurry, hurry, hurry!
ニャー　もう自分
昨日から 水しか飲んでません
Oh, I'm falling! I haven't had anything but water since yesterday!
Lying
Come on, not when I'm holding the pot!
（あかり）うわあ もう
お鍋 危ないってば
ヒナ　ニャーたちに ご飯あげて
あと お皿並べてちょうだーい
Hina, feed the kitties!
And please set the table!
Okay!
（ひなた）はーい
（ひなた）お姉ちゃん
零君 勝ったって
Sis, Rei said he won!
I see.
そう
So good! Nummy, nummy, nummy!
（クロちゃん）うめ〜 うめ うめ…
（あかり）さあ 食べようね
All right, let's eat.
あっ こら ヒナ
仏様のごはんにカレーを？
Wait, Hina! You're putting curry on the altar as an offering?!
Huh? Should I not?
えっ ダメ？
I mean, Mom and Grandma loved curry.
だって お母さんもおばあちゃんも
カレー 大好きだったから
I wanna put a soft-boiled egg up there too!
Still, curry isn't exactly...
だからといって カレーは…
ああ… でも 好きだったよね
確かに
They did really like it.
Well, I suppose it's okay.
まあ 正しいか…
モモもカレー大好き！
I love curry too!
お母さん おばあちゃん
今日のカレーは豚コマですよ〜
Mom, Grandma, tonight's curry has pork in it!
Well, everyone, shall we eat?
（あかり）じゃあ みんな
食べましょうか
Thank you for the food!
（ひなた･モモ）
いっただっきまーす！
Put eggs on my plate too!
（モモ）モモも 卵 のっけて
Yes, yes.
（あかり）はい はい
１個 食べられるかな？
Can you finish a whole egg?
Sure I can!
And now our next story.
（アナウンサー）
では 次のニュースです
On the 16th in Hibiya City,
police found the body of Unagawa Shizuo
日比谷市で 16日
会社員のウナガワシズオさんが—
in his home bludgeoned to death by a blunt instrument.
自宅で
鈍器のようなもので殴られ—
死亡しているのが
見つかった事件で—
行方不明になっていた
大学２年生になる—
His eldest son, Tadashi, a college sophomore
who had been reported missing, was arrested.
長男のタダシ容疑者を逮捕しました
調べによりますと—
According to the authorities,
Tadashi is suspected of murdering his father by striking him with a hammer dozens of times in the head.
父親の頭や顔などを
数十回にわたって—
ハンマーで殴り
死亡させた疑いです
Suspected of Murdering His Father by Striking Him with a Hammer Dozens of Times in the Head
（記者Ａ）
幸田さん 残念だったな
That's a shame for Kouda.
His league entrance after all this time was riding on that.
（記者Ｂ）久しぶりの
リーグ入りがかかってたのに
And to think his own son would beat him so easily.
まさか 息子に
ぶっちぎられるとはね
Although maybe he was satisfied after all.
ある意味 本望ってところかな
Suspected of Murdering His Father by Striking Him with a Hammer Dozens of Times in the Head
（記者Ａ）まあ…
本当の息子だったらの話だがな
Well, that'd probably only apply if he was his real son.
Every move I played felt like I was punching him with my bare hand.
（零）一手一手 まるで
素手で殴ってるような感触がした
殴った肌の温かさまで
生々しく残ってる気がする
The memory is so vivid that my hand feels warm when I remember it.
父さん…
Dad...
（ひなた）ん？
零君 どうしたの？ 寒い？
What's wrong, Rei?
Are you cold?
Huh?
Oh, uh...
Are you all right? Do you have a cold?
大丈夫？ 風邪かな？
何か温かいの 飲む？ 牛乳とか
Want something warm to drink?
Like milk, maybe?
It's an emergency!
大変だ〜！
Zoom
I'll warm up some milk for you!
あっためてきてあげる
Uh, um...
あと お薬も持ってくる
I'll bring medicine too!
あの すみません…
Um, sorry.
That's all right. You don't have to eat everything.
大丈夫 残してもいいよ
ゆっくりでいいから
Just take your time.
But you should eat a little.
でも ちょっとだけ食べなね
Okay.
はい
Hey!
（川本相米二(そめじ)）おう
What, the kid's sleeping already?
（相米二）何だ 坊主
もう寝てんのか？
行儀悪いな
食っちゃ寝か？
Talk about rude.
Ate and nodded off, did he?
He lay down after he finished eating.
（あかり）ごはんが終わったら
コロンとなっちゃったの
It was like he fainted.
気を失ったみたいに
（相米二）
対局の方は どうだったんだ？
How'd his match go?
He won, apparently.
（あかり）勝ったみたい
でも 真っ白な顔して来たわ
But he was pale when he got here,
and he barely ate.
ごはんも
ちょっとしか食べなかった
Yeah, can't blame him.
うーん それは無理もねえだろうな
I bet he couldn't get any sleep last night either.
そうか 夕べもどうせ
寝られなかったんだろ
Well, let him rest here for the night.
まっ 今日のところは
寝かせとけや
んじゃあ
俺もあっち戻って寝るわ
I'll go back to the shop and sleep there.
Tomorrow's bean roasting day.
明日 あんこ炊きの日だからな
Don't forget to lock up.
戸締り ちゃんとしろよ
Right.
（あかり）うん
おやすみ じいちゃん
Goodnight, Grandpa.
We'll help you stuff the pancakes tomorrow.
明日 どら焼き包みに行くから
（相米二）ああ 頼むわ
じゃあな　おやすみ
Yeah, please do!
Goodnight.
タオルケット 持ってきたよ
I brought you a blanket.
あっ 眼鏡したまま
Oh, he forgot to take off his glasses.
おやすみ
Goodnight.
（零）桐山零　これが僕の名前
Kiriyama Rei.
That's my name.
大きな川沿いの小さな町で
これから僕は暮らしてゆく
In a small town by a big river is where I'll be living from now on.
Ｃ級１組 五段 17歳
職業 プロ棋士
Class C1, 5-dan.
Seventeen years old.
Professional shogi player.
Kiriyama Rei
The Town by the River
Stare
A-An owl?
ふ… ふくろう？
Stare
No, it can't possibly be.
…な訳ないよね 普通
A magnificent white owl wouldn't
just show up at somebody's house.
民家に いきなり—
こんな ご立派な
シロフクロウいないよね
Plus, it's standing on the straw mat floor.
しかも いきなり畳の上に じかに
I'm pretty sure you're a cat, right?
君 猫だよね？ 多分
Oh no! I'm gonna be late!
大変！
遅刻しちゃうー！
はわわっ！
おはよう 零君！
Good morning, Rei!
Good morning!
（零）おはようございます！
Zoom
Here!
（ひなた）はい！
（零）あっ はい！
R-Right!
Bed head
（ひなた）お願い 混ぜて！
Please stir it!
（ひなた）た… 卵もお願い！
（零）はっ はい…
G-Get the eggs too, please!
Y-Yes!
Blunt
Well, I woke you up like I said I would.
（あかり）それじゃ　お姉ちゃん
ちゃんと起こしましたよ
Let's go, Momo.
（あかり）さあ 行きましょう モモ
（ひなた）私も今起きま〜す
I'm getting up now, don't worry.
See you later!
Even though Sis woke me up...
（ひなた）お姉ちゃんが
ちゃんと起こしてくれたのに…
Have a safe trip!
why did I fall back asleep?!
何でまた寝ちゃったんだろう
I'm gonna be late!
遅れるー
でも おいしいー
But this is so good!
Oh no, I'm running out of time!
大変だ〜　時間が〜
でも もう１杯〜
But one more bowl!
え？ まだ 食べるの？
What?! You're gonna have more?!
（ひなた）
うわっ 零君 これ持ってって
Rei, take this!
Your lunch! It's a bit big, but I pressed it together tightly, so it should be okay!
お弁当 ちょっとデカいけど
硬く握っといたから大丈夫
え？ あっ ありがとう
Th-Thank you!
And this is a strange side dish as a whole, but it's good!
（ひなた）あと
おかずといっては何だけど—
Ba-Baaaam!
（ひなた）これ 結構いいから
（零）あっ ありがとう
Grasp!
Th-Thank you!
I have morning practice, so I have to go!
それじゃ 朝練あるからお先に
どうぞ ごゆっくり
Take your time!
What?! U-Um, what about the key?
えっ あっ あの… 鍵は？
What?!
Here!
（ひなた）はい
閉めて出てください　よろしくです
Please lock up when you leave! Thank you!
W-Wait a second! If I have your key,
you won't be able to get in!
ちょっと ま…
俺が持って出たら
みんな入れないのでは？
Don't worry, we'll find a way in somehow!
大丈夫
なくても どっかからは入れるから
Baaaam
What?!
Shock
えー！ ダメ… じゃん
But that's wrong...
Silence...
Stare
I guess I'll try going to school.
（零）行ってみるかな 学校
Huh?
（林田(はやしだ)高志(たかし)）おろ 何だ 桐山
What's with that huge rice ball, Kiriyama?
でっかい握り飯だな
サッカーボール？
Or is it a soccer ball?
Mr. Hayashida.
先生
You're lucky to have rice.
（林田）いいな 米
俺 月末まで金無くて
このありさまだよ
I'm broke until the end of the month, so this is all I can get.
桐山たちってさ
対局料って月払いなの？
So, do you guys get paid monthly for your matches?
それとも 対局ごと振り込み？
Or do you get paid right after each match?
Monthly.
ああ 月払いです
銀行に普通に振り込まれます
They make bank deposits at the end
of the month for all matches played.
まとめて月末に
I've been following you online.
ネットでずっと
追っかけてたけどさ
お前 今 結構 勝ち進んでるから
対局数 多いよな
You've been on a winning streak,
so you must've played a lot of matches.
Let's see. The Shogi Dragon Tournament,
the Gold General Tournament, the Rookie Tournament...
えっと…
棋竜戦 玉将戦 新人戦…
ひ〜ふ〜み〜　うーん
One, two, three...
なあ 桐山
考えたくないんだけど—
Hey, Kiriyama.
I don't want to think about it...
お前 今 ひょっとして
俺より月給 高くね？
but is your monthly income more than mine?
くっそー！
God damn it!
What?!
Chompalicious
Dammit!
（林田）くそ！ お前なんかと
もう 昼飯一緒に食ってやんねえ！
I'm not going to eat lunch with you anymore!
（零）えー？
…っていうか 頼んでないし
What?!
Actually, I never asked you to.
If you don't like it, hurry up and make some friends!
悔しかったら早く友達作れ
学校で！
I'm an adult, so I'm really busy!
先生は大人だから 忙しいんだ！
What?
中学生でプロになって
天才とまで呼ばれた少年も—
Even though he turned pro during
junior high and is considered a prodigy,
ここでは普通の 悩める17歳か
at school he's just a 17-year-old with worries like anyone else.
一体 何を考えてるんだろうな…
I wonder what he's thinking about.
Welcome!
（ひなた）いらっしゃいませ
Oh, Rei! Welcome back!
（あかり）あら 零君 お帰りなさい
（ひなた･モモ）あっ
Was the rice ball good?
おにぎり おいしかった？
You're just in time.
（あかり）ちょうどよかった
手伝ってもらえるかな
Can you help us with something?
I'll tie the ribbons on,
so could you put six in a box and stack them up?
私がリボンをかけるから—
６個ずつ 箱に入れて
重ねてってくれる？
Oh, sure.
（零）ああ はい
助かるわ
じゃあ 手洗ってきて
That'd be a great help.
Go ahead and wash your hands first.
Egg
Chunky
（あかり）
きみあんとつぶあん ３個ずつね
Three egg bean paste and three chunky bean paste per box.
Got it.
（零）はい
Celebration
Cute wrapping paper, isn't it?
（あかり）かわいい かけ紙でしょ
Celebration
It's not printed, right?
印刷じゃないですよね
高そうだ
It looks expensive.
Actually, Hina made it.
実は これ ヒナが作ったのよ
Surprising, huh?
（あかり）びっくりでしょ
（零）あっ
It's potato print.
芋版だよ
I carved up sweet potatoes and stamped them on.
さつまいもを彫って押したの
Cute, right?
かわいいでしょ
（あかり）おじいちゃんのお友達の
お習字の先生の—
They're for Grandpa's calligraphy teacher friend, who's celebrating his 70th birthday.
70歳のお祝いの会のお土産なの
古希ってやつね
The big 7-0.
All right. Who did this one, I wonder?
Spirited
Away
All right.
Who did this one,
I wonder?
He taught Hina for a little while
when she was in elementary school.
（あかり）ヒナも小学生の頃
ちょっぴり習ってたんだよね
Me!
So this is her present to him.
だから これは
ヒナからのお祝いなのね
Hahaha, I suspected it was you, Hina.
Hahaha...
I suspected
it was you,
Hina.
Someji is very fortunate to have
grandchildren who are willing to help.
（おばあちゃんＡ）
幸せだね 相米二さんは
孫がみんな
こんなに手伝ってくれて
That's right. Someji is a lucky fellow.
（おばあちゃんＢ）そうだな
果報もんとは 相米二さんのことだ
What are you talking about?
何 言ってんでぇ
The little one tags along annoyingly
and is so loud that I can hardly stand it.
チビまでちょこまか付いてきて
うるさくてかなわねぇよ
Grandpa, look! I folded it myself!
おじいちゃん 見て
折れたの〜
Crumpled
うわ〜 すごいな　折り紙か
That's amazing!
Origami, huh?
Sorry.
（あかり）ごめんなさいね
You're so clever, Momo!
Grandpa is a bit of a softie when it comes to his grandkids.
おじいちゃん
ちょっと孫に弱くってね
Just a bit, huh?
（零）ちょっと… かな
（相米二）んじゃあ
ちょっくら 届けてくっからよ
Well, I'm off to deliver all this.
After that, I'm staying for the party, so take care of everything else.
そのまま 宴会に参加してくっから
後は よろしくな　じゃあ
Bye!
Well, shall we go?
さて 帰ろうか
零君 ごはん食べていくでしょ？
You'll eat dinner with us tonight, right?
Thanks for the offer, but I'll be going home tonight.
ありがとうございます
でも 今日は帰ります
また 対局…
試合あるし 練習しないと
I have another... another match, so I'd better practice.
I see.
（あかり）そう
（ひなた）試合多いね　頑張ってね
You have a lot of matches. Good luck.
Good luck!
頑張って
あ… あと おにぎり ありがとう
Also, thank you for the rice ball.
It was delicious.
おいしかったです
Here. Have this.
じゃあ これ うちの三日月焼
Our Baked Crescent.
Still piping hot.
できたてで おいしいよ
じゃあ おやすみなさい
Well, goodnight.
Come over anytime!
いつでも おいでね
待ってるから
We'll be waiting.
Goodnight!
おやすみ
頑張れ〜
Good luck!
まだ 来てないな
It still hasn't come.
（二海堂(にかいどう)晴信(はるのぶ)）ふふふふ…
（零）えっ！ ああ
Is this what you're looking for, Kiriyama Rei?
お探しのものは こちらかな
桐山零君
CHUB
Crisp
To Be Continued
Like a resplendent meteor shower
Your words enter my ears and catch fire
They come together like a school of fish
And form a warm corner in my once chilly bosom
As I stood in place, not knowing the right way to reach out
Your hand reached out to touch mine
And no matter how many nights may pass
That warmth still lingers and pulses within
Your very presence shines a bright light on every part of my life
Your racing heartbeat resonates with my frozen heart and sets it ablaze
Before long, the fire dies out
Leaving just one smoldering ember
Which remains with me and won't ever go away
Living inside of me in a place closest to my heart
Next Episode Preview
Episode 2
I see.
（あかり）そっか 桐山君は
私とヒナが作った料理より—
So he prefers instant noodles
over the food Hina and I cook.
カップ麺の方がおいしいのか
（二海堂）水くさいぞ 桐山！
親友だろう〜
Don't ignore me, Kiriyama!
We're friends, aren't we?!
（ひなた）ああ 零君だ！
Oh, it's Rei!
（零）助けて〜 花岡(はなおか)さ〜ん
Help me, Hanaoka!
（モモ）零ちゃん 見っけ！
I found Rei!
Illustration: Miura Kentarou
Please look forward to the next episode of
"March comes in like a lion."
（零）３月のライオン
次回もお楽しみに
よろしくお願いします